Srinivas Madnal

Senior Engineer - IT Quality & Assurance Testing

🗹 srinivas.madnal@gmail.com 🐧 +91 8553333850 💿 Bangalore,india 🌐 https://srinivasmadnal.netlify.app/

in Srinivas Madnal | LinkedIn 🔯 github.com/siri100



About Me

Professional Quality Assurance engineer with 4 years of experience in software quality process, Involved in end-to-end product testing and management across multiple platforms. I have experience in

Manual Testing, Web Automation, Mobile App **Automation, API Automation, Performance** Testing.

QA Skills

- **Manual Testing**
- JavaScript/TypeScript
- Selenium
- **Appium**
- **XCUITest**
- **UIAutomator**
- WebdriverIO
- Mocha
- **Azure Devops**
- Mobile Test AUtomation
- **API Test Automation**
- Web AUtomation
- TESTIM.IO
- BrowserStack
- SuperTest
- JIRA
- Cypress
- Load Runner
- Jenkins

PERSONAL PROJECTS

Mobile App Test Automation - Color-note Android App

Tech Stack: Appium.WebdriverlO,Mocha,Browserstack, Azure Devops CI/CD Pipeline

Maps API Test Automation project

Tech Stack: Javascrip, SuperTest. Mocha

Mobile App Test Automation - coindcxPro-note Android App

Tech Stack: Appium.WebdriverIO,Mocha,Browserstack, Azure Devops CI/CD Pipeline

Education Background

B-tech: Mechanical Engineering

Pes University 05/2014 - 05/2018,

Achievements

- Successfully reduced the regression cycle duration from 4 days to 2 hours by implementing a comprehensive test automation
- Star Award Winner Awarded for developing new Mobile App **Test Automation** framework
- Star Award Winner Awarded for Developing new framework for Production Smoke and Core Test cases in TESTIM.IO and for Securing passwords which reduced total Automation excution time from 90 mins to only 15 mins

Professional Experience

Senior Engineer - IT Quality & Assurance Testing | Marsh McLennan Global Services India Private Limited (MMGS) 2023 - Present

Key responsibilities:

- Developed Web Test Automation Framework: Designed and implemented a robust web test automation framework for Mercer Health application using WebdriverIO, TypeScript, Cucumber, and the Page Object Model (POM).
- Mobile App Test Automation : Developed a robust test automation framework for a hybrid mobile application using TypeScript, Mocha, Appium, and WebdriverIO, accommodating both iOS and Android test scripts in a scalable page object model.
- Custom Logging Mechanism: Introduced a custom logging mechanism within the automation framework to track and log detailed test execution results.
- API Test Automation: Integrated API test automation using SuperTest to facilitate test data management through APIs, and to write integration tests ensuring comprehensive test coverage.
- Test Data Management: Managed test data within the automation framework using Excel files, enabling efficient datadriven testing.
- Extensive Scripting: Scripted over 500+ user stories into automation scripts for both regression and smoke testing, significantly enhancing test coverage and reliability.
- Continuous Integration and Delivery (CI/CD): Integrated the test automation framework into **Jenkins** and **Azure** Pipelines to enable automatic test execution and result reporting during release cycles.
- Manual QA Testing: Performed manual QA testing for migration projects from on-premises infrastructure to AWS, ensuring smooth transitions and system integrity.
- Load and Performance Testing: Developed scripts for load and performance testing using LoadRunner to assess system performance under various conditions during migration projects.
- Stakeholder Management: Collaborated with multiple stakeholders during the development of automation scripts and the submission of regression automation reports with them.

QA Automation Engineer | Amiti software technologies Pvt Ltd. 2020 - 2023

Key responsibilities:

- Developed New Mobile App Test Automation framework using Typescript, Mocha, Appium, Webdriver IO.
- Developed New web app Test Automation framework using Typescript, Mocha, Webdriver IO.
- Developed and maintained Mobile automation scripts for around 10 Android .apk , IOS .ipa Apps
- Developed and maintained web app automation scripts for around 80 web sites.
- Created Detailed and Clear documentation on Mobile App Test Automation Strategy.
- Responsible for integrating Mobile Test-Automation Framework with BrowserStack and MS Azure ADO Pipelines .
- Responsible for developing new framework, Planning and maintaining Production/Non-Production Smoke Tests and Core Test automation scripts in TESTIM.IO.
- Worked as Code Reviewer For Smoke Tests, Integration tests and End-to-End tests.
- Responsible for Securing Production and non-Production passwords in all existing Automation frameworks.